<Datasets>
  <Common>
    <Field name="chi">
      <summary>
        Community Health Index (CHI) number is a unique personal identifier allocated to each patient on first registration with a GP Practice. It follows the format DDMMYYRRGC where DDMMYY represents the persons date of birth, RR are random digits, G is another random digit but acts as a gender identifier, (where odd numbers indicate males and even numbers indicate females), and the final digit is an arithmetical check digit.
      </summary>
    </Field>
  </Common>
  <Maternity>
    <summary>
		Tayside and Fife births record.  Contains the parents and children birthed during the admission.  This data is provided in a format based upon the Scottish SMR02 dataset
	</summary>
  <Field name="MotherCHI">
		<summary>  
			Unique identifier of the pregnant mother of the baby being born
     </summary>
	</Field>
  <Field name="SendingLocation">
		<summary>  
			This field indicates the location of where the data was sent from. This is not necessarily the same place as where the episode took place.
     </summary>
	</Field>
  <Field name="EpisodeRecordKey">
		<summary>  
			Unique identifier indicating a specific case record
     </summary>
	</Field>
  <Field name="MaritalStatus">
		<summary>  
			This field represents the mothers marital status.  At a certain date ISD stopped using numbers in this column and started using letters.  If this field contains a letter (A-Z),
     </summary>
	</Field>
  <Field name="Speciality">
		<summary>  
			A specialty is defined as a division of medicine or dentistry covering a specific area of clinical activity and identified within one of the Royal Colleges or Faculties.
     </summary>
	</Field>
  <Field name="Location">
		<summary>  
			This field represents the location code at which health activity takes place. In other words, the location code represents the point of delivery of health care. 
     </summary>
	</Field>
  <Field name="Healthboard">
		<summary>  
			Single letter code describing which NHS healthboard the record came from e.g. T for Tayside, F for Fife
        </summary>
	</Field>
    <Field name="Date">
		<summary>  
			The date of admission to the birthing unit
        </summary>
	</Field>
    <Field name="PartnerCHI">
		<summary>  
			Unique identifier of the second contributor of genetic material for the babie(s) being born or null if baby is a clone
        </summary>
	</Field>
        <Field name="BabyCHI1">
		<summary>  
			Unique identifier of the first baby to be born
        </summary>
	</Field>
        <Field name="BabyCHI2">
		<summary>  
			Unique identifier of the second baby to be born (if twins)
        </summary>
	</Field>
        <Field name="BabyCHI3">
		<summary>  
			Unique identifier of the third baby to be born (if triplets)
        </summary>
	</Field>
  </Maternity>
  <Biochemistry>
    <summary>
      Tayside and Fife labs biochemistry data.  This data is provided in a format based upon the SCI-Store system.
    </summary>
    <Field name="ArithmeticComparator">
		<summary>  
			This field represents additional information to be used in conjunction with the numeric result field Result. 
			The contents should be interpreted along with the Result, for example, some EGFR results may be reported as Result = 60, with ArithmeticComparator = '>'  
			This means the result is greater than 60.
		</summary>
		</Field>
		<Field name="Interpretation">
		<summary>  
      Contains comments regarding the result.
		</summary>  
		</Field>
    <Field name="Healthboard">
      <summary>
        This is the alpha and/or numeric Health Board code in which the patient CHI information was extracted from. 
      </summary>
    </Field>
    <Field name="SampleDate">
      <summary>
        This is the date and time when the sample was taken from the patient.
      </summary>
    </Field>
    <Field name="SampleType">
      <summary>
        The type of sample that was run e.g. 'Blood', 'Serum' etc.
      </summary>
    </Field>
    <Field name="TestCode">
      <summary>
        This field store the test code for the test taken/performed (e.g., CHOL = Cholesterol) as used by the providing organisation.  This is the internal lab system identifier for the test being run (See ReadCodeValue for a coded answer).  Includes non clinical/message codes such as ECOM.
      </summary>
    </Field>
    <Field name="Result">
      <summary>
        Numerical measure captured during the test (expressed in QuantityUnit units)
      </summary>
    </Field><Field name="LabNumber">
      <summary>
        This is a unique identifier assigned by the lab system to identify a sample run.  Each sample run can have multiple tests run.
      </summary>
    </Field><Field name="QuantityUnit">
      <summary>
        The unit of measure that the Result is expressed in e.g. "mmol/L" / "umol/L".
      </summary>
    </Field>
    <Field name="ReadCodeValue">
      <summary>
        The read code allocated to the test.  This field is useful as a standardised grouping for the tests, for example, if you are looking in Serum Total Cholesterol, all records marked with 44P. represent this regardless of the TestCode provided.
      </summary>
    </Field>
    <Field name="RangeLowValue">
      <summary>
        Minimum guideline value for the test result at the time of testing.  These ranges vary based on relevant criteria such as age, gender, and guidelines will also change over time.
      </summary>
    </Field>
    <Field name="RangeHighValue">
      <summary>
        Maximum guideline value for the test result at the time of testing.  These ranges vary based on relevant criteria such as age, gender, and guidelines will also change over time.
      </summary>
    </Field>
	</Biochemistry>
  <Demography>
     <summary>
       Address and patient details as might appear in the CHI register
      </summary>
    <Field name="Forename">
      <summary>
        Patients forename, randomly generated from a list of 100 common forenames that match the patients gender
      </summary>
    </Field>
    <Field name="Surname">
      <summary>
        patients surname, randomly generated from a list of 100 common surnames
      </summary>
    </Field>
    <Field name="ANOCHI">
      <summary>
        Annonymous identifier that has replaced the identifiable CHI.  Typically represented as aaa1234567 where the first three letters uniquely identify a project (allowing for project specific anonymisation)
      </summary>
    </Field>
    <Field name="DateOfBirth">
      <summary>
        Date of birth of the patient, this should match the first 6 digits of the CHI 
      </summary>
    </Field>
    <Field name="DateOfDeath">
      <summary>
        If the patient is dead then this date will be filled in with the date it occured
      </summary>
    </Field>
    <Field name="Gender">
      <summary>
        M for Male patient, F for Female patient.  Should match the second last digit of the CHI (if the patient has a CHI and not an ANOCHI) with odd numbers for females and even numbers for males.  This reflects the physical sex at birth and not what the person may identify as now.
      </summary>
    </Field>
    <Field name="Address">
      <summary>
        The address which the patient lives at at the time of the EHR record being generated
      </summary>
    </Field>
    <Field name="PreviousAddress">
      <summary>
        The previous address which the patient lived at when the EHR record being generated
      </summary>
    </Field>
	<Field name="dtCreated">
	<summary>
	The date the patient registerd with the GP (when the chi record was created).
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="current_record">
	<summary>
	1 if the record is still active in the given healthboard (e.g.. Tayside) or 0 if a more recent record exists in another healthboard (i.e. they are known to have moved out of the area or if ISD no longer supplies the record). Note that if your research project only covers Tayside then you would not nessesarily get a record with 1 if they moved to Glasgow but would still get the old record from Tayside with 0 for current record. 
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="notes">
	<summary>
	
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="chi_num_of_curr_record">
	<summary>
	Indicates that the chi number recorded (in the chi field) is out of date and that the person should actually be known by this alias.  This occurs when a patient doesn't know thier chi or is unable to 
	supply it (e.g. an emergency appointment while on holiday).
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="chi_status">
	<summary>
	Indicates whether the chi record is current or not, see lookup z_chiStatus
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="century">
	<summary>
	This field contains a 2-digit century of when a person was born (e.g., 19 = born between 1800 - 1899 ; 20 = born between 1900 - 1999; and 21 = born from 2000 onwards).
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="current_address_L1">
	<summary>
	Current known patient address line 1
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="current_address_L2">
	<summary>
	Current known patient address line 2
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="current_address_L3">
	<summary>
	Current known patient address line 3
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="current_address_L4">
	<summary>
	Current known patient address line 4
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="current_postcode">
	<summary>
	Current patient's Postcode 
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="source_death">
	<summary>
	Contains a C if the source of the death information is CHI snapshots, or a G if the source of the death was General Registrar of Deaths (GRO).  If the information is in both GRO and CHI then the code GC will appear.
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="area_residence">
	<summary>
	Healthboard that the patient is currently residing in (may be different from the healthboard they are registered with - hb_extract)
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="hb_extract">
	<summary>
	This field represents the alpha and/or numeric Health Board code in which the patient CHI information was extracted from. 
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="current_gp">
	<summary>
	GP Code of the patients currently registered GP
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="birth_surname">
	<summary>
	Patients surname at birth
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="previous_surname">
	<summary>
	Patients previous surname (e.g. if married)
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="midname">
	<summary>
	Patients middle name
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="alt_forename">
	<summary>
	An alternative name patient goes by
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="other_initials">
	<summary>
	Middle name initials (if any) the patient goes by
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="previous_address_L1">
	<summary>
	Patients previous address line 1
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="previous_address_L2">
	<summary>
	Patients previous address line 2
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="previous_address_L3">
	<summary>
	Patients previous address line 3
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="previous_address_L4">
	<summary>
	Patients previous address line 4
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="previous_postcode">
	<summary>
	Patients previous address postcode
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="date_address_changed">
	<summary>
	The date when the patient moved from thier previous address to the current address.
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="adr">
	<summary>
	
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="current_gp_accept_date">
	<summary>
	This is the date when the patient was accepted onto current GP list. 
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="previous_gp">
	<summary>
	GP Code of the patients previously registered GP
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="previous_gp_accept_date">
	<summary>
	Date patient registered with previous GP
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="date_into_practice">
	<summary>
	This field represents the date when a person came into the health board region and registered with that health board GP. 
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="patient_triage_score">
	<summary>
	
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="hic_dataLoadRunID">
	<summary>
	Indicates which data load execution batch (if any) was responsible for creating the record
	</summary>
	</Field>
  </Demography>
  <Prescribing>
  <summary> 
	Prescription data of prescribed drugs 
  </summary>
  <Field name="ResSeqNo">
      <summary>
        Unique number identifying a prescribable drug
      </summary>
    </Field>
	<Field name="Quantity">
      <summary>
        The number prescribed to the patent e.g. 12
      </summary>
    </Field>
	<Field name="Strength">
      <summary>
        The strength of the drug prescribed e.g. "2.5 MG"
      </summary>
    </Field>
	<Field name="StrengthNumerical">
      <summary>
        The numerical portion of Strength e.g. 50 (must be combined with MeasureCode)
      </summary>
    </Field>
	<Field name="FormulationCode">
      <summary>
        How the drug is provided e.g. "TABS", "CREAM"
      </summary>
    </Field>
	<Field name="MeasureCode">
      <summary>
        The units portion of Strength e.g. MG
      </summary>
    </Field>
	<Field name="Name">
      <summary>
        The common/proprietary name for the drug being prescribed e.g. VENTOLIN
      </summary>
    </Field>
	<Field name="ApprovedName">
      <summary>
        The standardised name/active drug e.g. SALBUTAMOL
      </summary>
    </Field>
	<Field name="BnfCode">
      <summary>
        Machine readable formatting of Bnf 0407010Q0AAAAAA
      </summary>
    </Field>
	<Field name="FormattedBnfCode">
    <summary>
        Human readable formatting of Bnf e.g. 4.7.1
      </summary>
    </Field>
	<Field name="BnfDescription">
    <summary>
        Lookup description of what the Bnf entry means
      </summary>
    </Field>
  </Prescribing>
  <CarotidArteryScan>
  <summary> 
	Carotid ultrasound is a procedure that uses sound waves to examine the blood flow through the carotid arteries (in your neck).

Carotid ultrasound tests for blocked or narrowed carotid arteries, which can increase the risk of stroke.
  </summary>
  <Field name="RECORD_NUMBER">
	<summary>
	
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="R_CC_STEN_A">
	<summary>
	
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="R_CC_STEN_B">
	<summary>
	
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="R_CC_STEN_C">
	<summary>
	
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="R_CC_STEN_D">
	<summary>
	
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="R_CC_STEN_S">
	<summary>
	
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="L_IC_STEN_A">
	<summary>
	
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="L_IC_STEN_B">
	<summary>
	
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="L_IC_STEN_C">
	<summary>
	
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="L_IC_STEN_D">
	<summary>
	
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="L_IC_STEN_S">
	<summary>
	
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="R_IC_STEN_A">
	<summary>
	
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="R_IC_STEN_B">
	<summary>
	
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="R_IC_STEN_C">
	<summary>
	
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="R_IC_STEN_D">
	<summary>
	
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="R_IC_STEN_S">
	<summary>
	
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="COMMENT">
	<summary>
	
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="REPORT">
	<summary>
	This is a free text field
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="id">
	<summary>
	
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="PatientID">
	<summary>
	
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="SUMMARY">
	<summary>
	
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="LAST_AUTH_BY">
	<summary>
	
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="LAST_AUTH_DT">
	<summary>
	
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="CV_FILE">
	<summary>
	
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="L_CC_STEN_S">
	<summary>
	
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="CV_DT">
	<summary>
	
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="PROV_REPT_DT">
	<summary>
	
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="FILE_COPY_DT">
	<summary>
	
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="LAST_UPDATED_DT">
	<summary>
	
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="AUTHORISED_DT">
	<summary>
	
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="REPT_STATUS">
	<summary>
	This field represents the report status 0, unlocked unauthorised 1, locked authorised 2, unlocked previously authorised report reopened for amendment 
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="STUDIES">
	<summary>
	 This field represents Workload measure for this exam
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="FINAL_REPT_DT">
	<summary>
	
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="hic_dataLoadRunID">
	<summary>
	
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="L_CC_STEN_D">
	<summary>
	
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="L_CC_STEN_B">
	<summary>
	
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="APPT_ID">
	<summary>
	
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="DATE">
	<summary>
	Date of appointment.
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="CHINO">
	<summary>
	
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="L_BD_RATIO">
	<summary>
	This field represents Left IC End diastolic flow/Left CC End diastolic flow
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="L_AC_RATIO">
	<summary>
	This field represents Left IC Peak systolic flow/Left CC Peak systolic flow 
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="R_BD_RATIO">
	<summary>
	 This field represents Right IC End diastolic flow/Right CC End diastolic flo
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="R_AC_RATIO">
	<summary>
	This field represents Right IC Peak systolic flow/Right CC Peak systolic flow
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="L_CC_STENOSIS">
	<summary>
	This field represents Left Common Carotid % StenosisReferences Lookup Table z_PCStenosisLookup 
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="L_CC_PEAK_SYS">
	<summary>
	This field represents Left Common Carotid Peak Systolic Flow
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="L_CC_END_DIA">
	<summary>
	This field represents Left Common Carotid End Diastolic Flow
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="L_IC_STENOSIS">
	<summary>
	This field represents Left Internal Carotid % StenosisReferences Lookup Table z_ICStenosisLookup
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="L_IC_PEAK_SYS">
	<summary>
	This field represents Left Internal Carotid Peak Systolic Flow
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="L_IC_END_DIA">
	<summary>
	This field represents Left Internal Carotid End Diastolic Flow
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="L_EC_STENOSIS">
	<summary>
	This field represents Left External Carotid StenosisReferences Lookup Table z_StenosisLookup 
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="L_PLAQUE">
	<summary>
	This field represents Left side PlaqueReferences Lookup Table z_PlaqueLookup
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="L_SYMPTOMS">
	<summary>
	This field represents Left symptoms
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="L_BRUIT">
	<summary>
	This field represents a left bruit (audible vascular sound)
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="L_CC_STEN_A">
	<summary>
	
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="ON_STEN_STUDY">
	<summary>
	
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="R_VERT_ARTERY">
	<summary>
	This field represents Right Vertebral Artery FlowReferences Lookup Table z_VertflowLookup
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="R_BRUIT">
	<summary>
	This field represents right bruit (audible ventricular noise)
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="R_SYMPTOMS">
	<summary>
	This field represents Right symptoms
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="R_PLAQUE">
	<summary>
	This field represents Right side PlaqueReferences Lookup Table z_PlaqueLookup
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="L_CC_STEN_C">
	<summary>
	
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="R_EC_STENOSIS">
	<summary>
	This field represents Right External Carotid StenosisReferences Lookup Table z_StenosisLookup
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="R_IC_PEAK_SYS">
	<summary>
	This field represents Right Internal Carotid Peak Systolic Flow
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="R_IC_STENOSIS">
	<summary>
	This field represents Right Internal Carotid % StenosisReferences Lookup Table z_ICStenosisLookup
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="R_CC_END_DIA">
	<summary>
	This field represents Right Common Carotid End Diastolic Flow
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="R_CC_PEAK_SYS">
	<summary>
	This field represents Right Common Carotid Peak Systolic Flow
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="R_CC_STENOSIS">
	<summary>
	This field represents Right Common Carotid % StenosisReferences Lookup Table z_PCStenosisLookup 
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="L_VERT_ARTERY">
	<summary>
	This field represents Left Vertebral Artery FlowReferences Lookup Table z_VertflowLookup
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="R_IC_END_DIA">
	<summary>
	This field represents Right Internal Carotid End Diastolic Flow
	</summary>
	</Field>
  </CarotidArteryScan>	
  <HospitalAdmissions>
  <summary>
  Dataset records admissions to hospital and the reason for admission (presenting condition(s)).
  </summary>
  <Field name="DateOfBirth">
	<summary>
	Date patient was born
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="AdmissionDate">
	<summary>
	Date patient was admitted to hospital
	</summary>
	</Field><Field name="DischargeDate">
	<summary>
	Date patient was discharged from hospital (or died).
	</summary>
	</Field><Field name="MainCondition">
	<summary>
	The primary presenting condition and the reason for hospitalisation.  This is either an ICD10 code or an ICD9 code.  ICD9 codes are preceeded by a minus symbol to distinguish them.
	</summary>
	</Field><Field name="OtherCondition1">
	<summary>
	The second condition for hospitalisation.  This is either an ICD10 code or an ICD9 code.  ICD9 codes are preceeded by a minus symbol to distinguish them.
	</summary>
	</Field><Field name="OtherCondition2">
	<summary>
	The tertiary condition for hospitalisation.  This is either an ICD10 code or an ICD9 code.  ICD9 codes are preceeded by a minus symbol to distinguish them.
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="OtherCondition3">
	<summary>
	The forth condition for hospitalisation.  This is either an ICD10 code or an ICD9 code.  ICD9 codes are preceeded by a minus symbol to distinguish them.
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="Comment">
	<summary>
	Free text field
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="MainOperation">
	<summary>
	The main operation is that selected by the clinician responsible for the care of the patient. Part A is used for single codes or for the primary part of a recognised code-pair. 
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="MainOperationB">
	<summary>
	The main operation is that selected by the clinician responsible for the care of the patient. Part B is used for Core Approach, Technique, Site or Laterality codes or for the supplementary part of a recognised code-pair. 
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="OtherOperation1">
	<summary>
	This field represents other operation entered in the order specified by the clinician. Part A is used for single codes or for the primary part of a recognised code-pair.
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="OtherOperation1B">
	<summary>
	This field represents other operation entered in the order specified by the clinician. Part B is used for Approach, Technique, Site or Laterality codes or for the supplementary part of a recognised code-pair. 
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="OtherOperation2">
	<summary>
	This field represents other operation entered in the order specified by the clinician. Part A is used for single codes or for the primary part of a recognised code-pair.
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="OtherOperation2B">
	<summary>
	This field represents other operation entered in the order specified by the clinician. Part B is used for Approach, Technique, Site or Laterality codes or for the supplementary part of a recognised code-pair. 
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="OtherOperation3">
	<summary>
	This field represents other operation entered in the order specified by the clinician. Part A is used for single codes or for the primary part of a recognised code-pair.
	</summary>
	</Field>
	<Field name="OtherOperation3B">
	<summary>
	This field represents other operation entered in the order specified by the clinician. Part B is used for Approach, Technique, Site or Laterality codes or for the supplementary part of a recognised code-pair. 
	</summary>
	</Field>
  </HospitalAdmissions>
</Datasets>
