<Datasets>
  <Common>
    <Field name="chi">
      <summary>
        Community Health Index (CHI) number is a unique personal identifier allocated to each patient on first registration with a GP Practice. It follows the format DDMMYYRRGC where DDMMYY represents the persons date of birth, RR are random digits, G is another random digit but acts as a gender identifier, (where odd numbers indicate males and even numbers indicate females), and the final digit is an arithmetical check digit.
      </summary>
    </Field>
  </Common>
  <Biochemistry>
    <summary>
      Tayside and Fife labs biochemistry data.  This data is provided in a format based upon the SCI-Store system.
    </summary>
    <Field name="ArithmeticComparator">
		<summary>  
			This field represents additional information to be used in conjunction with the numeric result field Result. 
			The contents should be interpreted along with the Result, for example, some EGFR results may be reported as Result = 60, with ArithmeticComparator = '>'  
			This means the result is greater than 60.
		</summary>
		</Field>
		<Field name="Interpretation">
		<summary>  
      Contains comments regarding the result.
		</summary>  
		</Field>
    <Field name="Healthboard">
      <summary>
        This is the alpha and/or numeric Health Board code in which the patient CHI information was extracted from. 
      </summary>
    </Field>
    <Field name="SampleDate">
      <summary>
        This is the date and time when the sample was taken from the patient.
      </summary>
    </Field>
    <Field name="SampleType">
      <summary>
        The type of sample that was run e.g. 'Blood', 'Serum' etc.
      </summary>
    </Field>
    <Field name="TestCode">
      <summary>
        This field store the test code for the test taken/performed (e.g., CHOL = Cholesterol) as used by the providing organisation.  This is the internal lab system identifier for the test being run (See ReadCodeValue for a coded answer).  Includes non clinical/message codes such as ECOM.
      </summary>
    </Field>
    <Field name="Result">
      <summary>
      </summary>
    </Field><Field name="LabNumber">
      <summary>
        This is a unique identifier assigned by the lab system to identify a sample run.  Each sample run can have multiple tests run.
      </summary>
    </Field><Field name="QuantityUnit">
      <summary>
        The unit of measure that the Result is expressed in e.g. "mmol/L" / "umol/L".
      </summary>
    </Field>
    <Field name="ReadCodeValue">
      <summary>
        The read code allocated to the test.  This field is useful as a standardised grouping for the tests, for example, if you are looking in Serum Total Cholesterol, all records marked with 44P. represent this regardless of the TestCode provided.
      </summary>
    </Field>
    <Field name="RangeLowValue">
      <summary>
        Minimum guideline value for the test result at the time of testing.  These ranges vary based on relevant criteria such as age, gender, and guidelines will also change over time.
      </summary>
    </Field>
    <Field name="RangeHighValue">
      <summary>
        Maximum guideline value for the test result at the time of testing.  These ranges vary based on relevant criteria such as age, gender, and guidelines will also change over time.
      </summary>
    </Field>
	</Biochemistry>
  <Demography>
     <summary>
       Address and patient details as might appear in the CHI register
      </summary>
    <Field name="Forename">
      <summary>
        Patients forename, randomly generated from a list of 100 common forenames that match the patients gender
      </summary>
    </Field>
    <Field name="Surname">
      <summary>
        patients surname, randomly generated from a list of 100 common surnames
      </summary>
    </Field>
    <Field name="ANOCHI">
      <summary>
        Annonymous identifier that has replaced the identifiable CHI.  Typically represented as aaa1234567 where the first three letters uniquely identify a project (allowing for project specific anonymisation)
      </summary>
    </Field>
    <Field name="DateOfBirth">
      <summary>
        Date of birth of the patient, this should match the first 6 digits of the CHI 
      </summary>
    </Field>
    <Field name="DateOfDeath">
      <summary>
        If the patient is dead then this date will be filled in with the date it occured
      </summary>
    </Field>
    <Field name="Gender">
      <summary>
        M for Male patient, F for Female patient.  Should match the second last digit of the CHI (if the patient has a CHI and not an ANOCHI) with odd numbers for females and even numbers for males.
      </summary>
    </Field>
    <Field name="Address">
      <summary>
        The address which the patient lives at at the time of the EHR record being generated
      </summary>
    </Field>
    <Field name="PreviousAddress">
      <summary>
        The previous address which the patient lived at when the EHR record being generated
      </summary>
    </Field>
  </Demography>
  <Prescribing>
  <summary> 
	Prescription data of prescribed drugs 
  </summary>
  <Field name="ResSeqNo">
      <summary>
        Unique number identifying a prescribable drug
      </summary>
    </Field>
	<Field name="Quantity">
      <summary>
        The number prescribed to the patent e.g. 12
      </summary>
    </Field>
	<Field name="Strength">
      <summary>
        The strength of the drug prescribed e.g. "2.5 MG"
      </summary>
    </Field>
	<Field name="StrengthNumerical">
      <summary>
        The numerical portion of Strength e.g. 50 (must be combined with MeasureCode)
      </summary>
    </Field>
	<Field name="FormulationCode">
      <summary>
        How the drug is provided e.g. "TABS", "CREAM"
      </summary>
    </Field>
	<Field name="MeasureCode">
      <summary>
        The units portion of Strength e.g. MG
      </summary>
    </Field>
	<Field name="Name">
      <summary>
        The common/proprietary name for the drug being prescribed e.g. VENTOLIN
      </summary>
    </Field>
	<Field name="ApprovedName">
      <summary>
        The standardised name/active drug e.g. SALBUTAMOL
      </summary>
    </Field>
	<Field name="BnfCode">
      <summary>
        Machine readable formatting of Bnf 0407010Q0AAAAAA
      </summary>
    </Field>
	<Field name="FormattedBnfCode">
    <summary>
        Human readable formatting of Bnf e.g. 4.7.1
      </summary>
    </Field>
	<Field name="BnfDescription">
    <summary>
        Lookup description of what the Bnf entry means
      </summary>
    </Field>
  </Prescribing>
</Datasets>